Young Master
젊은 스승
Aying
아잉
Slower
느리게
Ah Ying, how is your injury?
아잉, 부상은 어때요?
Don't worry, sir, I'm fine
걱정하지 마세요 선생님 저는 괜찮아요
It's just a skin injury
그냥 피부 상처일 뿐이야
It's you
당신이에요
Seriously injured
심각하게 부상당한
Come and drink the medicine first
먼저 와서 약을 마셔라
Drink quickly
빨리 마셔
Ah Ying, my injury doesn't matter
아잉, 부상은 상관없어
Let's quickly rendezvous with the army
군대와 빨리 만나자
How about going back to Yingzhou?
잉저우로 돌아가는 게 어때요?
no
아니요
Young Master's injuries
젊은 스승의 부상
I've already asked Taozi
나는 이미 Taozi에게 물었습니다.
And those healers?
그리고 그 치료사?
they all said
그들은 모두 말했다
Be sure to do well
꼭 잘 지내세요
take some rest
좀 쉬세요
Aying
아잉
Just to recuperate
단지 회복을 위해서
You can't recuperate here either.
여기서도 회복할 수 없습니다.
look
바라보다
This is where the Zhenxi Army is located
여기는 진시군이 있는 곳이다
Li Yi detained you and me again
리이가 당신과 나를 또 구금했어요
I'm afraid he has a plan
그 사람에게 계획이 있는 것 같아 걱정이에요
The current situation in Yingzhou
영주현 상황
Very critical
매우 중요
You know
알잖아
The Zhenxi Army took Luoyang by itself
진희군은 낙양을 스스로 점령했다.
He already holds half of the mountains and rivers in his hands
그는 이미 산과 강의 절반을 손에 쥐고 있다.
He has a problem with our Cui Jiajun again
그는 또 우리 Cui Jiajun에게 문제가 있습니다
I'm afraid of him
나는 그를 두려워한다
The Zhenxi Army will not act like this
Zhenxi 군대는 이렇게 행동하지 않을 것입니다
Do you think Zhenxi Army
당신은 Zhenxi 군대를 생각하십니까
Not so
별로
I still think Li Yi would not be like this
나는 아직도 리이가 이렇지 않을 것이라고 생각한다.
Sun Jing has not been eliminated
Sun Jing은 제거되지 않았습니다.
The Zhenxi Army is also the division of King Qin
진희군은 진왕의 사단이기도 하다.
anyway
그래도
Neither can the Zhenxi Army
진시군도 마찬가지다
To our Cui Jiajun
우리 최자준에게
Act like this
이렇게 행동하세요
Sun Jing is in danger
손진이 위험해
All the passes have been lost, the passes have been broken
패스가 모두 손실되었습니다. 패스가 깨졌습니다.
His army of one hundred thousand
그의 군대는 십만이요
Conquering Baiyue in the south again
다시 남쪽의 백월을 정복하다
Li Yiruo points his sword at West Changjing
리이루오가 서창징을 향해 칼을 겨누고 있다.
Sun Jing, in addition to sticking to his
Sun Jing은 자신의 말을 고수하는 것 외에도
no other way
다른 방법은 없어
He only has the forbidden army now
이제 그는 금지된 군대만 가지고 있습니다.
Li Yiruo captured Xichangjing
리 이루오(Li Yiruo)가 서창징(Xichangjing)을 점령했습니다.
Until then
그때까지
Just to take your head and mine
너와 내 머리를 가져가려고
to coerce father
아버지를 강요하다
Coercing Cui Jiajun
최자준을 강요하다
Young Master is worrying too much
영스승님은 걱정이 너무 많아요
Don’t say that Xichangjing is now
Xichangjing이 지금이라고 말하지 마세요
Impregnable
난공불락
Even if one day
어느 날이라도
Li Ni captured Xichangjing
Li Ni가 Xichangjing을 점령했습니다.
Neither will he
그도 마찬가지일 것이다
How does it treat our Cui Jiajun?
Cui Jiajun을 어떻게 대합니까?
Are you being raped by Li Yi?
리이에게 강간당하고 있나요?
Drink the ecstasy soup
엑스터시 수프를 마셔라
Do you
당신은 ~
To put Cui Jiajun’s safety at risk
Cui Jiajun의 안전을 위험에 빠뜨리기 위해
Disregarding his father's safety
아버지의 안전을 무시하고
So determined
그래서 결정
to be gullible
속기 쉽다
A frivolous villain?
경솔한 악당?
Young Master
젊은 스승
I'm talking about things
나는 이것저것 얘기하고 있어
Aying
아잉
The young master’s injury has not healed yet
젊은 스승님의 부상은 아직 낫지 않았습니다
It’s better to meditate and recuperate
명상하고 회복하는 것이 더 좋습니다
Aying Aying
아잉 아잉
Gongzi Gongzi
공지공지
school lieutenant
학교 중위
Although this secret medicine is extremely good
이 비약은 아주 훌륭하지만
But you still have to pay attention to your wound
하지만 그래도 상처는 조심해야 해
Be sure to avoid food
음식은 꼭 피하세요
Otherwise you will leave scars
그렇지 않으면 흉터가 남을 것입니다.
Okay, got it
알겠습니다. 알겠습니다
Very good
매우 좋은
Why do you have to climb through the window to get in?
왜 창문을 통해 올라가야 들어가나요?
When I just came in
방금 들어왔을 때
Met Taozi
도자와 함께
She doesn't let me bring outside food
그녀는 내가 외부 음식을 가져오는 것을 허락하지 않는다
So I had no choice but to climb through the window
그래서 창문으로 올라갈 수밖에 없었어
Look what I have prepared for you
내가 너를 위해 무엇을 준비했는지 봐
grand grandson
손자
I thought it was some kind of treasure
뭔가 보물인줄 알았는데
Just a few pancakes
팬케이크 몇 개만 먹어도
Actually
실제로
And a bowl of meat
그리고 고기 한그릇
I want you to eat a burrito
부리또 먹고 싶어
But I was outside the window just now
그런데 지금은 창밖에 있었어
I heard Taozi say that you should avoid food
도자가 음식을 피해야 한다고 말하는 걸 들었어요
Can't eat meat
고기를 먹을 수 없다
So I ate the meat
그래서 고기를 먹었어요
Just make do with it for you
그냥 당신을 위해 그것을 해결
Have a piece of cake
케이크 한 조각 드세요
What's so strange about this cake?
이 케이크의 뭐가 그렇게 이상한가요?
It’s worth bringing to Emperor Sunba Baba
순바바바 황제께 가져갈 가치가 있습니다
Not surprising at all
전혀 놀라운 일이 아니다
I just know you have a poor appetite
나는 단지 당신이 식욕이 좋지 않다는 것을 알고 있습니다.
Branded especially for you
당신을 위해 특별히 만들어진 브랜드
Since I can’t eat meat
고기를 못먹으니까
Then dip it in some honey and eat it
그럼 꿀에 찍어서 드세요
This is rare
이것은 드물다
Where does this honey come from?
이 꿀은 어디서 나오는 걸까요?
Afternoon
오후
I'm on the mountainside under a rock
나는 산허리 바위 아래에 있어요
Found a beehive
벌집을 발견했습니다
So I told Lao Bao
그래서 나는 라오바오에게 말했다.
Go and pick it off
가서 골라내세요
This bowl of honey
이 꿀 한 그릇
Enough to feed you for several days
며칠 동안 먹을 수 있을 만큼
You need to take medicine to recover from your injuries
부상을 회복하려면 약을 복용해야 합니다.
If it’s hard to take medicine
약을 먹기 힘들다면
Just drink it with honey.
꿀과 함께 마시면 됩니다.
correct
옳은
I have something to ask you
물어볼 게 있어요
What's the matter?
무슨 일이야?
I will tell you everything
나는 당신에게 모든 것을 말할 것입니다
Nothing to say
말할 것이 아무것도 없어
Emperor's grandson
황제의 손자
How do you plan to regain West Changjing?
서창징을 어떻게 되찾을 계획인가요?
if i tell you
내가 당신에게 말하면
I'm at a loss
난 헤매고 있어
Do you believe it or not?
믿거나 말거나?
I believe it
난 그것을 믿는다
If it were me
나라면
I will also be at a loss
나도 당황하겠지
Western Kyoto, Kyoto
Western Kyoto, Kyoto
Taizu conquered one hundred thousand people
타이즈는 십만 명을 정복했다
Sixteen years of construction
16년간의 건설
Impregnable
난공불락
Sun Jing
순징
Famous generals in the world
세계의 유명한 장군들
He once conquered Gaoji three times
그는 한때 Gaoji를 세 번 정복했습니다.
His ability to defend the city
도시를 방어하는 그의 능력
It's much more powerful than our siege.
우리 공성전보다 훨씬 더 강력해요.
Not to mention siege
포위는 말할 것도 없고
It is much more difficult than defending the city.
도시를 방어하는 것보다 훨씬 더 어렵습니다.
and
그리고
Sun Jing is a cold and cruel person
Sun Jing은 차갑고 잔인한 사람입니다
almost invulnerable
거의 무적
you say
당신은 말한다
Can I not be helpless?
무력할 수는 없나요?
Now he sends a large army to fight against Baiyue
이제 그는 백월에 맞서 싸우기 위해 대규모 군대를 보냅니다.
They also sent a large group of troops north to Yingzhou.
그들은 또한 북쪽의 잉저우(Yingzhou)로 대규모 군대를 보냈습니다.
actually
실제로
He doesn't have many soldiers at his disposal
그에게는 마음대로 쓸 수 있는 병사가 많지 않다.
There are also 100,000 forbidden troops
금지된 병력도 10만명
Keep it for defending the city.
도시를 방어하기 위해 보관하세요.
Imperial Guard
제국 근위대
Originally the teacher of the emperor's personal general
원래는 황제의 개인 장군의 스승이었다.
Can it be shaken?
흔들릴 수 있을까?
It was the Imperial Guard who rebelled in the first place.
처음에 반란을 일으킨 것은 제국 근위대였습니다.
Otherwise Sun Jing
그렇지 않으면 Sun Jing
Able to rely on one's own strength
자신의 힘으로 의지할 수 있는
Subvert Chao Gang and kill the late emperor
조강을 전복시키고 고제를 죽인다
Kill the kings?
왕들을 죽여?
Trapped and surrounded
갇히고 둘러싸여 있다
trapped and surrounded
갇혀 있고 포위되어 있다
This is a plan
이것은 계획이다
Now Sun Jing is hoarding food again
이제 Sun Jing은 다시 음식을 비축하고 있습니다.
To prepare for siege
포위 공격을 준비하려면
A city like Xichangjing
시창징과 같은 도시
Even if it lasts a year and a half
1년 반이 지나도
It’s not necessarily possible to break the city.
도시를 파괴하는 것이 반드시 가능한 것은 아닙니다.
At that time
그때에
Sun Jing is sure
쑨징은 확실해
The army that conquered Baiyue has been recalled
바이웨를 정복한 군대가 소환되었습니다
Let's attack from both front and back
앞뒤 모두 공격하자
Even if we join forces then
그때 우리가 힘을 합쳐도
You may not be able to win this round
이번 라운드에서 승리하지 못할 수도 있습니다
What if
만약
I have a plan
난 계획을 가지고있어
Can break the city
도시를 무너뜨릴 수 있다
Is the emperor's grandson willing?
황제의 손자가 의향이 있습니까?
Promise me something
나한테 뭔가 약속해줘
are you willing to stay
당신은 머물 의향이 있습니까?
Join me in defeating West Changjing
나와 함께 West Changjing을 격파하세요
Do you want to surround Wei and save Zhao?
웨이를 포위하고 자오를 구하고 싶나요?
To relieve Yingzhou's difficulties, right?
Yingzhou의 어려움을 완화하기 위해 그렇죠?
If we can break West Changjing
서창징을 깰 수 있다면
Or force Sun Jing to
아니면 Sun Jing에게 강제로
Those who were besieged in Yingzhou
영주에서 포위된 사람들
Return troops and horses
군대와 말을 반환
The siege of Nayingzhou was solved
나잉저우(Nayingzhou) 포위 공격이 해결되었습니다.
I promise you
약속 할게
Even if you tell me ten thousand things
만가지 말을 해도
I can promise you anything
난 무엇이든 약속할 수 있어요
The emperor's grandson is really
황제의 손자는 정말
Only seeing the immediate benefits
당장의 이익만 보고
If I can't break the city
내가 도시를 무너뜨릴 수 없다면
Then you
그럼 당신은
You can't promise me anything anymore
넌 이제 나한테 아무것도 약속할 수 없어
That's not true
그건 사실이 아니야
If you can't break the city
도시를 무너뜨릴 수 없다면
I can promise you
약속할 수 있어요
Nine thousand nine hundred and ninety-nine things
구천구백구십구 가지
But you have to promise me one thing
그런데 한 가지 약속해 주셔야 해요
What's the matter?
무슨 일이야?
Haven't thought about it yet
아직 생각해본 적 없어
Wait until I think about it
내가 생각할 때까지 기다려
It's not too late if you promise me again
다시 한번 약속해도 늦지 않아
Why such a weird statement?
왜 그렇게 이상한 말을 하는 걸까요?
I always feel
나는 항상 느낀다
what are you planning
너는 무엇을 계획하고 있니?
do not worry
걱정 하지마
I won't let Lieutenant He
나는 그 중위를 허락하지 않을 것이다
You are in trouble
당신은 곤경에 처해 있습니다
What about me?
나는 어때?
I won't make it difficult for you either
나도 널 힘들게 하지 않을게
Saburo
사부로
The scouts found out
스카우트들이 알아냈어
Cui Lin and He
추이린과 그
After being rescued by Li Yi
리이에게 구출된 후
Recuperating in Aoguan
아오관(Aoguan)에서 요양 중
It was hard to fake it
가짜로 만드는 게 힘들었어요
Secret letter from uncle who is ill
아픈 삼촌의 비밀편지
Also Cui Lin and He's family
또한 Cui Lin과 그의 가족
Defraud the Chinese Army
중국군을 속여라
Want to kill in one fell swoop
한방에 죽이고 싶다
Who knew that Li Yi would appear?
리이가 나타날 줄 누가 알았겠어요?
Now the two of them are hiding in Auguan
지금 두 사람은 아우구안에 숨어있습니다
There's nothing we can do
우리가 할 수 있는 일은 아무것도 없어
Hello Li Ni
안녕하세요 리니님
Ruined my good deeds again
내 선행을 또 망쳤어
Sanlang, don't worry
Sanlang, 걱정하지 마세요
Cui Lin and He's soldiers and horses
추이린과 그의 병사들과 말들
Not much left
얼마 남지 않았습니다
The Cui family's army was also blocked on the way
추이 가문의 군대도 도중에 막혔습니다
It's impossible for them
그들에겐 불가능해
Stayed in Aoguan
아오관에 숙박함
As long as we wait patiently
우리가 인내심을 갖고 기다리는 한
You can always find an opportunity to strike again
언제든지 다시 공격할 기회를 찾을 수 있습니다.
Send me orders
나에게 주문을 보내주세요
Set up camp near Aoguan
Aoguan 근처에 캠프를 설치하세요
besides
게다가
Let the scouts investigate closely
정찰병들이 면밀히 조사하도록 하세요
Cui Lin and the whereabouts of the He family
추이린과 허씨 가문의 행방
Once the two of them leave Aoguan,
두 사람이 아오관을 떠나자,
That's when they die
그 때 그들은 죽는다
yes
예
Young Master
젊은 스승
You might as well
당신도 그럴 수도 있어요
You might as well get a knife
칼을 얻을 수도 있다
kill me
나를 죽여라
you listen to me
당신은 내 말을 들어요
If we can fight with the Zhenxi Army
진희군과 싸울 수 있다면
Let’s break the city together
함께 도시를 무너뜨리자
The siege of Yingzhou will be lifted immediately
영주 포위는 즉시 해제될 것이다
The Zhenxi Army cannot be trusted gullibly
Zhenxi 군대는 속기 쉽게 신뢰할 수 없습니다
Moreover
게다가
Besides, West Changjing
게다가 서창징(West Changjing)도
Once someone knows your identity
누군가가 당신의 신원을 알고 나면
What a dangerous thing that is
그게 얼마나 위험한 일이냐
Young Master
젊은 스승
Sun Jing has always been a traitor in the world
Sun Jing은 항상 세상의 반역자였습니다.
But he is arrogant
하지만 그 사람은 거만해요
He would never have thought that Li Yi and I
그 사람은 Li Yi와 내가
Dare to sneak into Xichangjing alone?
감히 혼자 서창징에 몰래 들어갈 수 있나요?
That's not allowed
그건 허용되지 않아요
just in case
혹시라도
If there is an emergency in Xichangjing
서창징에 긴급상황이 발생하면
The siege of Yingzhou must be lifted
잉저우 포위 공격을 해제해야 합니다
If this is a game of Zhenlong
이것이 진롱게임이라면
Then this move is the chess move.
그렇다면 이 동작이 체스 동작입니다.
Don't say anything
아무 말도 하지 마세요
I won't let you go
나는 당신을 보내지 않을 것입니다
The young master cares about Yingzhou
젊은 스승은 영주를 걱정한다
But I'm worried about my safety
하지만 안전이 걱정돼요
But I've decided to go
하지만 난 가기로 결정했어
Sir, don’t worry
선생님, 걱정하지 마세요
Even if things are not harmonious
일이 조화롭지 않더라도
I will definitely be able to return safely
반드시 무사히 돌아올 수 있을 거예요
Aying
아잉
I plead
나는 간청한다
can you not go
너는 가지 않을 수 있니?
Young master me
영 마스터 나
Ah Ying, I'm really worried about you
아잉, 정말 걱정돼
If you are
당신이있는 경우
If you were trapped in West Changjing
서창징에 갇혔다면
How do you want me to see my handsome father?
잘생긴 아버지를 어떻게 만나길 바라나요?
if you are true
당신이 사실이라면
Lost in West Changjing
서창징에서 길을 잃다
I will never redeem myself
나는 결코 나 자신을 구원하지 않을 것이다
Young Master
젊은 스승
I've made up my mind
난 결심했어
Ah Shu, take good care of the young master
아슈, 젊은 스승님을 잘 보살펴주세요
Aying
아잉
Young Master
젊은 스승
You might as well get a knife
칼을 얻을 수도 있다
Kill me now
지금 나를 죽여라
Keep me out of sight
나를 눈에 띄지 않게 해주세요
Not that much
그다지 많지는 않다
OK OK
그래 그래
You just told me
방금 나한테 말했잖아
Are you planning to go with He?
그 분과 함께 갈 계획이신가요?
Disguised and sneaked into Xichangjing
변장하고 시창징(Xichangjing)에 몰래 들어갔다.
Plan to seize the city
도시를 점령할 계획
yes
예
Are you still right with me?
아직도 나랑 잘 지내?
OK
좋아요
I'm going to find the rope now
이제 밧줄을 찾으러 가겠습니다
I tied myself up
나는 나를 묶었다
I don’t need my father to ask me
아버지가 나한테 물어볼 필요는 없어
I asked him myself
나는 그에게 직접 물었다.
Go and ask for forgiveness
가서 용서를 구해라
I'll go now
지금 갈게
wrong
잘못된
I should tie you up
널 묶어야겠어
Send them back to the rear camp of the Zhenxi Army
그들을 진희군 후방 진영으로 돌려보내라
Arrived at father's place
아버지 집에 도착함
Even if you want to overturn the world
세상을 뒤집고 싶어도
It's none of my business anymore
더 이상 내 일이 아니야
General Pei's rear camp
페이 장군의 후방 캠프
Thousands of miles away from here
여기에서 수천 마일 떨어진 곳
As long as you don't say
당신이 말하지 않는 한
He won't know
그 사람은 모를 거야
What's the rush?
서두르는 이유는 무엇입니까?
Jushichiro
주시치로
Think about it yourself
스스로 생각해 보세요.
You are now the coach of Zhenxi Army
당신은 이제 Zhenxi 군대의 코치입니다
You and He
당신과 그 사람
unarmed
비무장
I'm going to go to West Changjing
나는 서창징으로 갈 예정이다
If someone by Sun Jing
만약 Sun Jing의 누군가가
Found it
그것을 발견
That's the wolf entering the tiger's mouth
늑대가 호랑이 입으로 들어가는 거군요
You will never come back
당신은 결코 돌아 오지 않을 것입니다
Who said there are only two of us?
누가 우리 둘만 있다고 했어?
I also plan to take Lao Bao with me
나도 라오바오를 데리고 갈 생각이야
And long ears
그리고 긴 귀
Who said we were bare-handed?
우리가 맨손이라고 누가 말했습니까?
We will definitely carry weapons.
우리는 반드시 무기를 가지고 다닐 것입니다.
Don't tell me this
나에게 이런 말을 하지 마세요
Anyway, I won't allow you to go
어쨌든, 나는 당신이 가는 것을 허락하지 않을 거예요
If you are worried
걱정된다면
Come with us
우리와 함께
I can't even go
난 갈 수도 없어
right
오른쪽
you can't go
넌 갈 수 없어
We need you to guard Aoguan here.
여기서 아오관을 지켜주셔야 합니다.
Just stay here
그냥 여기 있어
Wait for my good news
내 좋은 소식을 기다려주세요
OK OK OK
오케이 오케이 오케이
After sneaking into Xichangjing
Xichangjing에 몰래 들어간 후
what's your plan
당신의 계획은 무엇입니까
What are your plans?
당신의 계획은 무엇입니까?
No plan, act by ear
계획은 없고 귀로만 행동하라
What
무엇
lied to you
당신에게 거짓말을 했어요
Don't worry, I must have a plan
걱정하지 마세요. 계획이 있을 거에요.
Even if something happens
무슨 일이 일어나도
I will also look for opportunities to escape
나도 탈출할 기회를 찾아보겠다
But we need you here in Aoguan
하지만 여기 Aoguan에는 당신이 필요해요
Stay here
여기있어
Don't worry about the rest
나머지는 걱정하지 마세요
do you know
당신은 알고 있나요
if you get stuck in
만약 당신이 갇히게 된다면
words from xichangjing
시창징의 말
I have no choice at all
나에게는 선택의 여지가 전혀 없다
save you
당신을 구해주세요
They will definitely take you by then
그땐 분명 널 데려갈 거야
Threaten the entire Zhenxi Army
Zhenxi 군대 전체를 위협
That's natural
그건 당연해요
do not worry
걱정 하지마
What if I really
만약 내가 정말로
Caught by Sun Jing
쑨징에게 붙잡혀
I've thought about it for you
나는 당신을 위해 그것에 대해 생각했습니다
Just say that you have been disobedient for a long time
당신이 오랫동안 불순종했다고 말하십시오
If you kill me
당신이 나를 죽이면
You, Pei, will definitely proclaim himself emperor to thank you.
당신 페이는 반드시 자신을 황제라고 선포하여 감사할 것입니다.
I promise
약속해요
Sun Jing will definitely be angry to death
Sun Jing은 분명히 화를 내며 죽을 것입니다.
Sun Jing is not mad at you
Sun Jing은 당신에게 화를 내지 않았습니다
I'm already mad at you
난 이미 너한테 화났어
Your Majesty, your Royal Highness is here.
폐하, 폐하께서 여기 계십니다.
Met the emperor's grandson
황제의 손자를 만나다
Miss Gu is too polite
구 선생님이 너무 예의바르세요
Qiucui, pour the tea quickly
Qiucui, 빨리 차를 부어
Miss Gu is here this time
구씨가 이번에 왔어요
one thing
한 가지
I want to ask Miss Gu
구씨에게 물어보고 싶어요
Your Majesty is welcome
폐하를 환영합니다
If there is a destiny, do whatever you want
운명이 있다면 하고 싶은 대로 해
Gu Xiang is in Beijing
구샹은 베이징에 있다
I would like to invite Miss Gu
구 선생님을 초대하고 싶습니다
Give me a token
토큰을 주세요
I want to send people to Beijing
사람들을 베이징으로 보내고 싶어요
Discuss with Xiang Gu to regain West Changjing
Xiang Gu와 논의하여 West Changjing을 되찾으세요.
Things that should be coordinated inside and outside
내부와 외부에서 조율해야 할 사항
If there is no token
토큰이 없는 경우
I'm afraid it's hard to win Prime Minister Gu's trust
구 총리의 신뢰를 얻기 어려울 것 같아 안타깝다.
The emperor and grandson want to send people to Beijing
황제와 손자는 사람들을 베이징으로 보내고 싶어한다
He must be a confidant
그 사람은 절친한 사람임에 틀림없어
That being the case
그렇긴 한데
No need for any tokens
토큰이 필요하지 않습니다.
Wan Niang is willing to go there in person
Wan Niang은 직접 그곳에 갈 의향이 있습니다
No
아니요
Going to see Prime Minister Gu is already a helpless move
구 총리를 만나러 가는 것은 이미 무력한 행보다.
Miss Gu can no longer be put in danger
구씨는 더 이상 위험에 빠질 수 없습니다
The emperor and his grandson help the world
황제와 그의 손자는 세상을 돕습니다
Now take back West Changjing
이제 West Changjing을 되찾으세요.
Everyone is responsible
모두가 책임이 있다
Although Wan Niang is a prostitute,
Wan Niang은 매춘부이지만,
I am also willing to contribute to the great cause of the world
나는 또한 세계의 위대한 대의에 기여할 의지가 있습니다
Try your best
최고의 노력을
My father is loyal to the country
아버지는 나라에 충성하신다.
I have been suffering for a long time
오랫동안 고생했어요
No matter what the emperor's grandson has planned
황제의 손자가 무슨 계획을 세웠다 해도
My father will definitely help me
아버지가 꼭 도와주실 거예요
Infiltration into Nishichokyo
니시초쿄에 잠입
Once discovered
일단 발견되면
It will be dangerous
위험할 거야
The emperor's grandson will definitely let Brother Xie
황제의 손자는 반드시 Xie 형제에게 허락할 것입니다
Brother Bao and others enter Beijing
바오 형제 등이 베이징에 입성하다
They are all battle-hardened
그들은 모두 전투에 단련되어 있습니다
A witty and brave person
재치 있고 용감한 사람
Wan Niang pretends to be a family member
Wan Niang은 가족인 척합니다
It's no problem
별거 아니야
Just in case something goes wrong
혹시라도 무슨 일이 생기면
Wan Niang will commit suicide
완니앙은 자살할 것이다
Never bring anyone down
절대로 누구도 끌어내리지 마세요
I have tasted this wine
나는 이 와인을 맛보았다.
The aroma of wine overflows
와인향이 넘친다
really not bad
정말 나쁘지 않아
This wine is from Luzhou
이 와인은 루저우(Luzhou)에서 생산된 와인입니다.
Why travel thousands of miles?
수천 마일을 여행하는 이유는 무엇입니까?
Ship it to Xichangjing
Xichangjing으로 배송
my master
나의 주인님
There is a wine shop in Beijing
베이징에 와인 가게가 있어요
Business has not been good these past two years
지난 2년간 사업이 좋지 않았다
The master is old
주인님은 늙으셨어요
Convenience young master
편의점 영마스터
Personally escort the wine to Beijing
와인을 직접 베이징까지 에스코트
Stop by the wine shop to check the bill
와인 가게에 들러 청구서를 확인해보세요
My young lady
나의 아가씨
My natal family was originally in Beijing
우리 가족은 원래 베이징에 있었어요
Follow me to Beijing this time
이번에는 나를 따라 베이징으로 가세요
Go back to your parents’ home to visit your elders
부모님한테 돌아가세요??? 어른들을 방문할 집
Jushichiro
주시치로
This was well planned beforehand
이건 사전에 잘 계획된 일이었어
Only Captain He
오직 그 선장이
One person pretends to be a female dependent
한 사람이 여성 의존자인 척합니다.
Now suddenly there is one more
이제 갑자기 하나 더 생겼네요
Miss Gu
미스구
Then what should I say?
그러면 뭐라고 말해야 할까요?
I can only say she is my sister.
나는 단지 그녀가 내 여동생이라고 말할 수 있다.
What about Miss Gu going there?
구씨 거기 가는 건 어때요?
Have you told Lieutenant He?
그 중위에게 말했나요?
said
말했다
Miss Gu
미스구
What about pretending to be your sister?
언니인 척 하는 건 어때요?
You also told Captain He
당신도 그 선장에게 말했어요
said
말했다
Then Lieutenant He didn't say anything else.
그러자 중위는 더 이상 아무 말도 하지 않았습니다.
She actually said
그녀는 실제로 말했다
You can also pretend to be her sister
당신도 그녀의 여동생인 척 할 수 있어요
It’s just that I think it’s disguised as
그냥 내가 보기엔 그게 위장된 것 같아
Aren’t everyone’s sisters the same?
자매는 다 똑같지 않나요?
It’s really different
??? 진짜 다르네
You
너
Hurry up and let Miss Gu
서둘러 구씨를 보내주세요
Let’s pretend to be Captain He’s sister
Captain He???의 여동생인 척 해보자
Lieutenant He, you are going too
그 중위님도 가세요
Yes
예
Huang Sun said
황순이가 말했다.
Miss Gu took the initiative to ask for help
구씨가 먼저 도움을 요청했습니다.
It's admirable
감탄스럽다
This is the right thing to do
이것이 옳은 일이다
Lieutenant He is overly praised
중위는 과하게 칭찬받는다
You and I pretend to be sisters
너와 나는 자매인 척
Don’t worry too much on the road
길에서 너무 걱정하지 마세요
Just play it by ear
그냥 귀로 연주해 보세요
Ready to go
갈 준비가 됐어요
Will the emperor and his grandson also ride with us?
황제와 그의 손자도 우리와 함께 탈 것인가?
No need, I'll ride a horse
필요없어 말을 탈게
Excuse me, you two, take the car.
실례합니다. 두 사람 모두 차를 타세요.
A Niang
아니앙
Our food
우리의 음식
Finally enough to collect and store food
마지막으로 음식을 모으고 저장하기에 충분합니다.
otherwise
그렇지 않으면
I still don’t know that I was killed by the military master
내가 군장에게 죽임을 당한 사실은 아직도 모른다.
Why are you in trouble?
왜 곤경에 처해 있나요?
Fortunately
다행스럽게도
I told you to Xu Jia Sanlang
Xu Jia Sanlang에게 말했어요
There's an order to stock up on food in this city.
이 도시에는 식량을 비축하라는 명령이 내려졌습니다.
Lady Xu
레이디 쑤
Send someone with a message immediately
즉시 다른 사람에게 메시지를 보내세요.
He said he had prepared food for us
우리를 위해 음식을 준비했다고 하더군요
Still talking
아직도 얘기 중
If it weren't for Xu Sanlang
Xu Sanlang이 아니었다면
Went to Tuzhou to sell cloth.
천을 팔러 투저우에 갔습니다.
I'm afraid I'll have to let Saburo take the food
사부로에게 음식을 가져가게 해야 할까봐 두렵습니다.
Send it to the city for us
우리를 위해 도시로 보내주세요
Madam Xu is so interested in you
Xu 부인은 당신에게 너무 관심이 있습니다
You will definitely be a loving mother-in-law in the future
당신은 앞으로도 분명 사랑받는 시어머니가 될 거예요.
A Niang
아니앙
Qiniang
치앙
A sergeant is coming
중사님이 오시네요
Lady Xu said
쉬 부인이 말했다.
People sent by Governor Sun Da
순다 지사가 보낸 사람들
Grabbing food everywhere
여기저기서 음식을 집는다
What should I do
어떻게 해야 하나요?
How do you cover this?
이것을 어떻게 덮나요?
Where to hide?
어디에 숨을 것인가?
Come and get my mother's clothes
와서 엄마 옷 좀 사다줘
Come quickly
빨리 오세요
Hurry this way
서둘러 이쪽으로
There's someone in front of you guys
너희 앞에 사람이 있다
well
잘
Go, go, go
가, 가, 가
Hurry up, hurry up
서둘러, 서둘러
Miss Gu, just ask whatever you want to ask.
구씨, 물어보고 싶은 건 뭐든 물어보세요.
Is the poison on the arrow in your sleeve quenched with poison?
소매에 꽂힌 화살의 독이 독으로 꺼지나요?
poisonous
유해한
But there is an antidote
하지만 해독제가 있어요
Wan Niang is just curious
Wan Niang은 단지 궁금할 뿐입니다.
Captain He is a girl
캡틴 그는 여자예요
Naturally there are many inconveniences in the military
당연히 군대에서 불편한 점이 많다.
But heroic
그러나 영웅적이다
Calm and free
조용하고 자유롭다
how to do it
어떻게 해야 할까?
What is a person like in person?
사람은 어떤 사람입니까?
Covering up cannot be covered up
은폐는 가릴 수 없다
That's how I was originally
나도 원래 그랬어
undisguised
변장하지 않은
Naturally, he is free and easy
당연히 그는 자유롭고 편하다.
Everything in the world
세상의 모든 것
Want something
뭔가를 원해
Nature will also be trapped by it
자연도 그것에 갇힐 것이다.
Miss Gu is a smart person
구씨는 똑똑한 사람이에요
I definitely understand
나는 확실히 이해한다
Thanks to Lieutenant He for his advice.
조언을 해주신 허중위님께 감사드립니다.
Spare us
우리를 살려주세요
please
제발
don't want
원하지 않는다
A Niang
아니앙
What's wrong
뭐가 문제 야
There's a lot ahead
앞으로 할 일이 많다
Someone is shouting for help
누군가 도와달라고 소리치고 있어요
Spare us
우리를 살려주세요
please
제발
A Niang A Niang
아니앙 아니앙
Auntie, please wake up.
아줌마, 일어나주세요.
Smelly bitches
냄새나는 년들
A Niang
아니앙
For a few bags of broken food
깨진 음식 몇 봉지 때문에
You dare to bite me
감히 날 물어뜯는구나
I won’t treat you today
오늘은 치료 안 할 거야
Chop it into pieces and feed it to the wolves
조각조각 잘라서 늑대들에게 먹이세요
It’s hard to understand the hatred in my heart
내 마음속에 있는 미움을 이해하기 어렵네요
Who?
WHO?
Your grandpa and I are here
네 할아버지와 내가 여기 있어
Take a slap from grandpa
할아버지한테 한 대 얻어맞아
Auntie, please wake up
아줌마 일어나주세요
A Niang
아니앙
Auntie, wake up
아줌마, 일어나요
It turned out to be Sun Jing's subordinate
알고 보니 쑨징의 부하였다.
No wonder he's so cruel
그 사람이 너무 잔인한 것도 당연하지
Either robbery or murder
강도든 살인이든
A Niang
아니앙
Auntie, wake up
아줌마, 일어나요
A Niang A Niang
아니앙 아니앙
Mom, are you awake?
엄마, 일어났어요?
A Niang
아니앙
Auntie, are you okay?
아줌마, 괜찮아?
right
오른쪽
These are the martyrs
이들은 순교자들이다
Passing by saved us
지나가다가 우리를 구했어
Thank you to all the martyrs for saving lives.
생명을 구해준 모든 순교자들에게 감사드립니다.
Auntie, you're welcome
이모님, 천만에요
We were passing by too
우리도 지나가던 중이었는데
Drawing a sword to help when the road is rough
길이 험난할 때 도움을 주기 위해 칼을 뽑는다
Those people are too bad
그 사람들 너무 나빠요
Not just stealing your stuff
물건을 훔치는 것뿐만 아니라
Killing innocent people indiscriminately
무고한 사람들을 무차별적으로 살해하는 행위
Those are all sergeants.
그 사람들은 모두 상사입니다.
I'm afraid there will be trouble
문제가 생길까 봐
All righteous men, please leave quickly.
의인 여러분, 빨리 떠나십시오.
Say it then
그럼 말해봐
They say my old woman is crazy
우리 할머니가 미쳤다고 하던데
Just wounded the sergeant
방금 상사에게 부상을 입혔어요
Grandma is fine
할머니는 괜찮아요
Those bad guys are dead
그 나쁜 놈들은 죽었어
The martyrs buried them all
순교자들이 다 묻어줬어요
They also spread grass on it
그 위에 풀도 깔아줬어요
Auntie is fine
아줌마는 괜찮아
Just don't worry
걱정하지 마세요
To save the old woman and the little girl
늙은 여자와 어린 소녀를 구하기 위해
Killed the sergeant
상사를 죽였습니다
If it is known to outsiders
외부인에게 알려진 경우
But I will be sent away by the official
하지만 나는 공무원에 의해 보내질 것이다
Catch Lingchi
링치 잡기
Auntie, don't worry
아줌마, 걱정하지 마세요
If you don’t say it, we won’t say it.
당신이 말하지 않으면 우리는 말하지 않을 것입니다.
No one will know
아무도 모를 거야
Auntie, it's getting late
아줌마, 시간이 늦어지네요
Take the little lady home quickly
꼬마 아가씨를 빨리 집으로 데려가세요
A few righteous men
몇몇 의로운 사람들
Please pay homage to the old woman
노부인에게 경의를 표해주세요
No, no, no, get up quickly
안돼 안돼 안돼 빨리 일어나
Get up quickly, Auntie
빨리 일어나세요 아줌마
A few righteous men
몇몇 의로운 사람들
That car is full of food
그 차에는 음식이 가득 차 있어요
The righteous man saved the lives of our mother and daughter
정의로운 분이 우리 어머니와 딸의 생명을 구하셨습니다
I'll give those grains to you.
그 곡물을 당신에게 주겠습니다.
No, thank you, auntie
아뇨, 고마워요 이모
We always bring dry food with us when we go out
우리는 외출할 때 항상 건조식품을 가지고 다닙니다.
You go to the city quickly
빨리 시내로 가세요
If it's later, you won't be able to get in.
그 이후라면 입장이 불가능합니다.
Come to Aniang
아니앙으로 오세요
Then thank you all the martyrs
그럼 모든 순교자들에게 감사드립니다.
life-saving grace
생명을 구하는 은혜
Thank you, martyr
고마워요, 순교자님
Miss Six
미스 식스
Why are you back?
왜 돌아왔나요?
Hard to describe in one word
한 단어로 설명하기 힘든
Go and inform your father quickly
가서 네 아버지께 빨리 알리라
Miss Six
미스 식스
Prime Minister is not feeling well today
총리님 오늘 몸이 안 좋으세요
Don't dare to disturb me at this time
지금은 감히 나를 방해하지 마세요
I have something urgent
급한 일이 있어요
If it's delayed
지연되는 경우
Can you afford it?
감당할 수 있나요?
What can Miss Six have?
Miss Six는 무엇을 가질 수 있습니까?
It's important
중요하다
I went to Bingzhou to pay homage to my father’s ancestors
나는 아버지의 조상에게 경의를 표하기 위해 Bingzhou에갔습니다.
Come back in a hurry
빨리 돌아와요
There must be something important
뭔가 중요한 게 있을 텐데
you a slave
너는 노예야
Block me out
나를 차단해
No notification
알림 없음
according to family rules
가족 규칙에 따라
Being perfunctory and contemptuous of the master
무뚝뚝하고 주인을 업신여긴다
what crime do you deserve
당신은 무슨 죄를 지을 자격이 있나요?
This sixth lady used to be a boring gourd
이 여섯 번째 여인은 지루한 조롱박이었습니다
Why did you suddenly become so powerful today?
오늘 갑자기 왜 이렇게 강해졌나요?
Miss Six is ​​serious
식스 씨는 ????????진심이에요
Miss Six, please come in quickly.
식스 씨, 빨리 들어오세요.
I'll pass it on right away
바로 전달할게요
you mean
네 말 뜻은
Seventeen emperors and grandsons sent capable people
17명의 황제와 손자들이 유능한 인재를 보냈습니다.
hope to meet me
나를 만나길 바라요
My daughter has been in Zhenxi Army recently
내 딸은 최근 Zhenxi 군대에 입대했습니다.
seen it myself
내가 직접 봤어
The seventeenth emperor's grandson was open-minded and generous.
17대 황제의 손자는 개방적이고 관대했습니다.
Able to conquer and fight well
잘 이겨내고 싸울 수 있는
Everyone in Zhenxi Army admired him
Zhenxi 군대의 모든 사람들이 그를 존경했습니다.
Now the emperor's grandson can go down to Aoguan
이제 황제의 손자가 아오관으로 내려갈 수 있게 되었습니다.
Half of the country is under control
국토의 절반이 통제되고 있다
what the people want
사람들이 원하는 것
Xichangjing is also in the bag
Xichangjing도 가방 안에 있어요
Although Sun Jing was brave for a while,
Sun Jing은 한동안 용감했지만
It’s just sitting in sleepy city
그냥 졸린 도시에 앉아 있는 것 뿐이야
Wan Niang
완니앙
You used to be in front of your father
넌 아버지 앞에 있었지
But I've never spoken like this
하지만 난 이런 말을 한 적이 없어
never said
말한 적 없어
So many words
너무 많은 단어
You used to belong to the imperial court
당신은 황실에 속해 있었습니다
Taiping Xiangguo
타이핑 샹궈
then be your daughter
그럼 당신의 딸이 되어주세요
It's naturally different from now
지금과는 자연스럽게 달라졌어
What's the difference?
차이점이 뭐야?
What do you think
어떻게 생각하나요
Be the daughter of the Prime Minister of Taiping
태평 총리의 딸이 되십시오
Just obey your parents
그냥 부모님한테 순종하세요
Honor your relatives, care for your siblings
친척을 공경하고 형제자매를 잘 돌보아라
I usually spend time admiring flowers and enjoying the moon
나는 주로 꽃을 감상하고 달을 즐기며 시간을 보낸다
Just listen to music and recite poems
음악을 듣고 시를 낭송해보세요.
What about now?
지금은 어때?
Father, you are in prison for Sun Jing
아버지, 당신은 Sun Jing 때문에 감옥에 갇혔습니다
Still unyielding
여전히 굴하지 않는
Many aristocratic families in Beijing take you as a role model
베이징의 많은 귀족 가문이 당신을 롤모델로 삼고 있습니다.
Even the emperor and grandson mentioned you
황제와 손자도 당신을 언급했어요
It’s also full of admiration
그것도 감탄이 가득
Be your daughter now
이제 당신의 딸이 되어주세요
Know how to understand the current situation
현재 상황을 이해하는 방법을 알아라
Understand the general trend of the world
세상의 대세를 이해하라
Tell your father everything you know
당신이 아는 모든 것을 아버지에게 말하라
Nothing to say
말할 것이 아무것도 없어
If the father feels
아버지가 느끼신다면
My little daughter
내 어린 딸
Still slightly usable
아직은 약간 쓸만함
Then Wan Niang was satisfied
그러면 Wan Niang은 만족했습니다.
Wan Niang
완니앙
once upon a time father
옛날에 아버지
I misjudged you
내가 당신을 잘못 판단했어요
Father is worried about state affairs
아버지는 국정을 걱정하신다
Pays little attention to family affairs
가족 문제에 거의 관심을 기울이지 않습니다.
Otherwise, with my father’s discerning eyes,
그렇지 않으면 아버지의 안목 있는 눈으로
How can you say that you saw it wrong?
어떻게 잘못 봤다고 말할 수 있나요?
Then tell me about it
그럼 그것에 대해 말해봐
These seventeen emperors and grandsons sent people to see me
이 17명의 황제와 손자들이 나를 만나러 사람들을 보냈습니다
What's the matter?
무슨 일이야?
Wan Niang apologizes to her father
완니앙, 아버지에게 사과하다
Just now Wan Niang deceived her father
방금 Wan Niang은 아버지를 속였습니다.
In fact, the seventeenth emperor's grandson
사실 제17대 천황의 손자
Didn't they send people here?
사람들을 여기로 보낸 게 아니었나요?
But he came by himself
그런데 그 분이 직접 오셨어요.
I want to interview my father
아버지를 인터뷰하고 싶어요
Miss Gu
미스구
Met the emperor's grandson
황제의 손자를 만나다
Miss Gu is too polite
구 선생님이 너무 예의바르세요
Invite me here
여기로 초대해주세요
But Mr. Gu agreed to meet him
하지만 구씨는 그를 만나기로 했다
yes
예
After Wan Niang returns home
완니앙이 집으로 돌아온 후
Explained to father
아버지께 설명함
The emperor's grandson has entered the city
황제의 손자가 도시에 들어왔다
Father is very happy
아버지는 매우 기뻐하십니다
I just want to come and see the emperor’s grandson in person right away
그냥 당장 황제 손자를 직접 보러 오고 싶을 뿐이에요
But after my father was released from prison
하지만 아버지가 감옥에서 석방된 후
Sun Jing has been sending people to monitor closely
Sun Jing은 면밀히 모니터링하기 위해 사람들을 보냈습니다.
Although my father can occasionally leave the house,
아버지는 가끔 집을 나가실 수도 있지만,
But there are always eyeliners following you
하지만 늘 따라다니는 아이라이너가 있어
The government doesn’t even know how to arrange it
정부는 어떻게 처리해야 할지조차 모르고 있다
How much eyeliner is there?
아이라이너는 얼마나 있나요?
Wan Niang pretended to go out of town today to offer incense
Wan Niang은 오늘 향을 제공하기 위해 마을 밖으로 나가는 척했습니다.
Specially invite the emperor’s grandson
황제의 손자를 특별히 초대하세요
I also asked the emperor and his grandson to come up with some ideas.
나는 또한 황제와 그의 손자에게 몇 가지 아이디어를 생각해 보도록 요청했습니다.
How can I get my father to get rid of the eyeliner?
어떻게 하면 아버지가 아이라이너를 지우시게 할 수 있나요?
Meet the emperor's grandson
황제의 손자를 만나다
Please rest assured, Miss Gu
안심하세요 구씨
it's natural
그것은 자연스럽다
I'm going back
나는 돌아갈 것이다
Think of a way
방법을 생각해 보세요
Definitely not
기필코 아니다
Making Sun Jing's spy suspicious
Sun Jing의 스파이를 의심하게 만들기
Thank you, Emperor Sun
감사합니다, 태양왕님
Miss Gu is too polite
구 선생님이 너무 예의바르세요
I should be the one to thank Miss Gu
미스 구에게 감사해야 할 사람은 나야
Since the emperor's grandson entered the city
황제의 손자가 도시에 들어온 이후로
But still safe
하지만 아직은 안전해요
We are all battle-hardened
우리는 모두 전투에 단련되어 있습니다
Although the capital is surrounded by dangers,
수도는 위험에 둘러싸여 있지만,
But not sinister
하지만 불길하진 않아요
Then Wan Niang is relieved
그러면 Wan Niang은 안도감을 느낍니다.
Wan Niang has one more thing to ask for.
Wan Niang은 한 가지 더 부탁할 것이 있습니다.
Please say
말해주세요
Wan Niang is faking today
Wan Niang은 오늘 가짜입니다
Come for incense
향을 받으러 오세요
I heard that the sacred tree of Qingyun Temple is efficacious
청운사 신목에 효능이 있다고 들었습니다
Break off a branch and soak it in the bath
가지를 꺾어 욕조에 담그세요
It can get rid of all diseases
모든 질병을 없앨 수 있다
If you don't break a branch and take it back
가지를 꺾지 않고 다시 가져오면
I'm just afraid that the government's informants will be suspicious
다만 정부 제보자들이 의심할까봐 두렵습니다.
Could you please invite the emperor's grandson?
황제의 손자를 초대해 주시겠어요?
Come with me to pick a branch
나랑 같이 가지 따러 가자
That's natural
그건 당연해요
Thank you, Emperor Sun
감사합니다, 태양왕님
It is said that sincerity leads to wisdom
성실이 지혜를 낳는다고 한다
Before breaking the branches of the sacred tree
신성한 나무 가지를 꺾기 전에
You must make a wish sincerely
진심으로 소원을 빌어야 해
Wish the person in your heart
마음속의 사람을 기원합니다
safe and sound
무사히
Is it this branch?
이 지점인가요?
Or the branch next to it?
아니면 옆에 있는 지점인가요?
beside
옆에
Thank you very much today
오늘 정말 고마워요
Thank you so much, Mr.
정말 고마워요, Mr.
No problem
괜찮아요
Miss Gu
미스구
Just call me Shichiro from now on.
이제부터는 그냥 시치로라고 불러주세요.
Good Shi7ro
좋은 시7로
Jushichiro
주시치로
Although the sacred tree is spiritual
신성한 나무는 영적인 나무이지만
But it’s discounted today
그런데 오늘은 할인됐어
I’m going to take a bath today
나 오늘 목욕할 거야
If you want to take it back
다시 가져가고 싶다면
To His Highness Prince Liang
양 왕자 전하께
I'm afraid it's a little too late.
조금 늦은 것 같아요.
The person I want to send to
보내고 싶은 사람
right in this city
바로 이 도시에서
They say this is outside the city
여기가 도시 밖이라고 하던데
The sacred tree in Qingyun Temple is very spiritual
Qingyun Temple의 신성한 나무는 매우 영적입니다.
I took a look
나는 살펴보았다
It turns out to be the Ping Po tree
핑포나무로 밝혀졌습니다
Branches and leaves can indeed relieve pain and remove toxins
가지와 잎은 실제로 통증을 완화하고 독소를 제거할 수 있습니다.
I have already ordered the store
이미 매장에서 주문했어요
I have prepared a large bucket of hot water for you
내가 너를 위해 큰 양동이의 뜨거운 물을 준비하였노라
Use it to soak in and bathe later
몸을 담그고 나중에 목욕할 때 사용하세요.
Good for your arrow wounds
화살 상처에 좋아요
You went outside the city
당신은 도시 밖으로 나갔습니다.
Gu Waanniang made an appointment with me
Gu Waanniang이 나와 약속을 잡았습니다
Meet at Qingyun Temple
청운사(Qingyun Temple)에서 만나기
Said that Gu Mansion can leave now
구맨션은 이제 나가도 된다고 하더군요
But can't leave the city
하지만 도시를 떠날 수는 없어
Moreover, there are eye spies all over the house and outside the house.
게다가 집 안팎에는 눈스파이들이 있다.
He always goes out now
그 사람은 이제 항상 밖에 나가
Everyone will be followed
모두가 따라갈 것이다
So if we want to meet
그러니 우리가 만나고 싶다면
You must think of a way
방법을 생각해야 해
I do
그래요
I thought of a good way
좋은 방법이 생각났어
There will be a good solution soon
곧 좋은 해결책이 나올 거예요
That won't happen soon
그런 일은 곧 일어나지 않을 거야
come up with a way
방법을 생각해내다
So that I can repay you for the kindness of breaking a branch.
가지를 꺾은 은혜에 보답할 수 있도록.
Unexpectedly, Li Yi
의외로 리이
He really rescued his father
그는 정말로 그의 아버지를 구출했다
Where now
지금은 어디에
He took the capital from the east and supported Aoguan Pass.
그는 동쪽에서 수도를 빼앗고 오관관을 지탱했다.
It's even approaching Xichangjing
시창징에도 가까워지네요
About to make a decision
결정을 내리려는 중
What an incredible achievement
정말 놀라운 성과네요
Although we have lost the opportunity now
지금은 기회를 잃었지만
But there is a way
하지만 방법이 있어요
Can reverse disadvantages
단점을 되돌릴 수 있음
tell me the story
나에게 이야기를 들려주세요
Big brother
형
Father as the first emperor
아버지가 첫 번째 황제
The only remaining bloodline
유일하게 남은 혈통
It’s the king’s honor again
또 왕의 영광이네
If it is from the father
아버지에게서 온 것이라면
If you inherit the throne
왕위를 물려받는다면
That couldn't be more justified.
그것은 더 이상 정당화될 수 없습니다.
If it is the father
만약 아버지라면
If you ascend the throne and become emperor in Dengdu,
만약 당신이 왕위에 올라 덩두에서 황제가 된다면,
Isn’t it true that there is no precedent in the country?
국내에 선례가 없다는게 사실 아닌가요?
Who supported the father?
아버지를 지지한 사람은 누구였나요?
When did you establish your father as king?
너는 언제 네 아버지를 왕으로 세웠느냐?
That's far better than capturing Aoguan.
그게 아오관을 잡는 것보다 훨씬 낫습니다.
Retaking West Changjing is much more important
West Changjing을 탈환하는 것이 훨씬 더 중요합니다.
This is the merit of support
이것이 지원의 장점이다
Big brother
형
you are the eldest son
당신은 큰 아들입니다
Once my father ascends the throne,
아버지가 왕위에 오르자마자
You are a first-class hero
당신은 일류 영웅입니다
Who else would you rather take the position of the East Palace?
동궁의 자리를 누가 대신하고 싶나요?
Furthermore
뿐만 아니라
Li Yi holds a heavy army
리이(Li Yi)는 중무장한 군대를 보유하고 있습니다.
He has repeatedly made military exploits
그는 반복적으로 군사적 공적을 세웠습니다.
But once my father ascends the throne,
하지만 아버지가 왕위에 오르자마자
His military exploits
그의 군사적 공적
It became a taboo in the DPRK
북한에서는 금기가 되었다
Second brother, what do you say?
둘째 형님, 뭐라고요?
It really enlightened me
정말 깨달음을 얻었습니다
only
오직
My father is now in Auguan
아버지는 지금 아우구안에 계시다
That Li Yi is full of tricks again
그 Li Yi는 또 속임수로 가득 차 있어요
What if Li Yi
만약 리이가
Don't let your father move to Luoyang
네 아버지가 낙양(洛陽)으로 이사가는 것을 허락하지 말라
So what?
그래서 뭐?
I still need to trouble my brother about this matter.
나는 아직도 이 문제로 내 동생을 괴롭혀야 합니다.
Go to Aoguan in person to welcome your father.
직접 아오관에 가서 아버지를 맞이하세요.
My father loves big brother the most.
아버지는 큰형을 가장 좋아해요.
If the elder brother goes there in person,
형이 직접 거기 가면
Father must be happy to agree
아버지도 기꺼이 동의하실 거에요
If Li Yi blocks it,
리이가 막으면
Then he is unfaithful and unfilial
그렇다면 그 사람은 불성실하고 불효한 사람이다.
That makes sense
말이 되네요
This makes sense
이것은 의미가 있습니다
do not worry
걱정 하지마
I will definitely remind my father in the future
앞으로는 꼭 아버지께 상기시켜 드리겠습니다
Make you a prince
당신을 왕자로 만들어주세요
Big brother
형
The most urgent task now
지금 가장 시급한 과제
It’s to welcome my father back.
아버지가 돌아오신 것을 환영하는 것입니다.
Will ascend the throne soon
곧 왕위에 오를 것이다
As for enfeoffment
집행에 관해서는
Don't be in a hurry
서두르지 마세요
I know brother means well
형이 좋은 뜻인 줄 알아
only
오직
I'm afraid that others will hate me
다른 사람들이 나를 미워할까 봐 두려워요
It's going to embarrass my elder brother
내 동생을 당황하게 할 거야
Second brother, are you sensible?
둘째 형님, 제정신이세요?
Met my sister-in-law
내 여동생을 만났어요
Husband's second brother
남편의 둘째 동생
I ordered the kitchen to stew some soup
나는 주방에 수프를 끓여달라고 명령했다
You have had a busy day
바쁜 하루를 보내셨나요
Use more or less
더 많든 적든 사용하세요
Thank you sister-in-law
고마워요 며느리
It's getting late
늦겠다
I won’t bother my brother and sister-in-law anymore.
나는 더 이상 내 형수와 형수를 괴롭히지 않을 것입니다.
Use some
일부를 사용
My second brother chatted with you for a long time tonight
오늘밤 우리 둘째 형이 너랑 오랫동안 수다를 떨었어
Did something happen?
무슨 일 있었어?
there is nothing
아무것도 없다
You don't have to worry too much
너무 걱정하지 않아도 돼요
It would be great if my third brother were here
내 셋째 동생이 여기 있으면 좋을 텐데
You three brothers
너희 세 형제
able to support each other
서로를 지지할 수 있는
Something's wrong
문제가 발생했습니다.
It can also be negotiated and measured
협상하고 측정할 수도 있습니다.
Your third brother is taller than your third brother.
당신의 셋째 동생은 셋째 동생보다 키가 더 큽니다.
You treat him as your brother
당신은 그를 형제처럼 대합니다.
That's not necessarily what he thought
그 사람이 꼭 그렇게 생각한 건 아니었어
In fact, the third brother's heart
사실 셋째 형의 마음은
I have always respected you
나는 항상 당신을 존경했습니다
this otherwise
그렇지 않으면
It is impossible to give up Luoyang
낙양을 포기하는 것은 불가능하다
He was willing
그는 기꺼이
Give up Luoyang?
낙양을 포기 하시겠습니까?
He is trying to rob Aoguan
그는 Aoguan을 강탈하려고합니다
Just attacking west Changjing
그냥 서쪽 창징을 공격해
Look at him on the surface
표면적으로 그를 좀 봐
A humble look
겸손한 모습
What is the reality?
현실은 무엇입니까?
It’s about seizing military success everywhere.
그것은 모든 곳에서 군사적 성공을 거두는 것에 관한 것입니다.
It was when you first got married
네가 처음 결혼했을 때였지
I just took care of him for a few days.
나는 단지 며칠 동안 그 사람을 돌봤을 뿐입니다.
Don't be deceived
속지 마세요
Okay, okay, you go back first
알았어 알았어 먼저 돌아가
I still have things to do
아직 할 일이 남아 있어
Let's go back
돌아가자
Jushichiro
주시치로
A message came from Aoguan
Aoguan에서 메시지가 왔습니다.
problem occurs
문제가 발생하다
What's wrong
뭐가 문제 야
King of Linzi
린자(臨子)의 왕
He brought the chariot himself
그는 마차를 직접 가져왔다
Picked up His Royal Highness Prince Liang from Aoguan
오관(Aoguan)에서 양왕 전하를 모셔왔습니다.
General Pei has no choice
페이 장군에게는 선택의 여지가 없다
I had no choice but to send someone to deliver a letter.
편지를 전달할 사람을 보내는 수밖에 없었습니다.
My brother
내 동생
Really all the time
정말 항상
all want to show
다들 보여주고 싶어
His filial piety
그의 효심
Win, win, win
승리, 승리, 승리
The mighty general
강력한 장군
King Lin Er said
린얼 왕이 말했다.
This cricket is a once-in-a-hundred-year experience.
이 크리켓은 백년에 한 번 있는 경험입니다.
Come, come, come
어떻게, 어떻게, 어떻게
Give you a cucumber to eat
오이를 주어 먹게 하라
What did you say about King Lin Er just now?
방금 Lin Er 왕에 대해 뭐라고 말하셨나요?
What are you talking about?
무슨 얘기를 하는 건가요?
King Lin Er
린 어 왕
Tell me about these days
요즘 얘기 좀 해줘
I heard you didn't sleep well
잠을 잘 못 잤다고 들었어
Looking for famous doctors everywhere
여기저기서 유명한 의사를 찾아요
He also asked Wu Guoshi
그는 또한 Wu Guoshi에게 물었다.
How to pray for you every day
매일 당신을 위해 기도하는 방법
Jun'er, this kid
준에르, 이 아이
Really thoughtful
정말 사려깊다
Your Highness
전하
Wu Guoshi said
우궈시가 말했다.
Are you a person with the destiny of a true dragon?
당신은 진정한 용의 운명을 가진 사람인가요?
The late emperor’s sons and grandsons
고(故) 황제의 아들과 손자
Only you can turn disaster into good fortune
당신만이 재난을 행운으로 바꿀 수 있다
Turn danger into safety
위험을 안전으로 바꾸세요
As soon as you ascend the throne
왕위에 오르자마자
That traitor Sun Jing
그 배신자 쑨징
Will be defeated immediately
즉시 패배할 것이다
For the sake of the people of the world
세계인들을 위하여
Your Highness, you must ascend the throne
전하, 왕위에 오르셔야 합니다
That's right
좋아요
For the people of the world
세계 사람들을 위해
I really should do this
나 이거 꼭 해야돼
should do this
이렇게 해야 해
Why did you bring me here?
왜 나를 여기로 데려왔나요?
This is the soy sauce garden
여기가 간장밭이에요
I was wronged when I was a child
나는 어렸을 때 부당한 대우를 받았습니다.
Or was beaten by his father
아니면 아버지에게 구타를 당하거나
Will secretly
비밀리에
Run here from the house
집에서 여기로 달려오세요
Then hide in this tree
그럼 이 나무에 숨어
While standing on this tree
이 나무 위에 서서
Watching the sky high, clouds and white birds chirping
높은 하늘을 바라보며 구름과 흰 새들이 지저귀는
every summer
매년 여름
Cicadas will still emerge from their shells here
매미는 여전히 이곳의 껍질에서 나옵니다.
Leave an empty cicada shell behind
빈 매미 껍질을 남겨두고
I picked up the cicada shell
매미 껍질을 주웠어요
Paint with ink
잉크로 칠하다
The result is just like a real cicada
결과는 진짜 매미와 똑같네요
Then I guess
그럼 내 생각엔
You must have used this as a false acknowledgment
이걸 허위 인정으로 이용했나 봐요
Go scare people
가서 사람들을 놀라게 해라
yes
예
Where is Li Jun?
리준은 어디에 있나요?
I'm most afraid of these insects.
나는 이 곤충을 가장 무서워한다.
once
한 번
He knocked the ink onto the book
그는 책에 잉크를 두드렸다
But he slandered me
그런데 그 사람이 나를 비방했어요.
I was beaten by my father
나는 아버지에게 구타당했습니다.
I can't be angry
화를 낼 수가 없어
I'll take that empty cicada shell
그 빈 매미 껍질을 가져갈게요
put it on his desk
그 사람 책상 위에 올려놔
The results of it
그 결과
Scared him so much that he screamed
너무 무서워서 비명을 질렀다.
alright
괜찮은
This time he went to complain again
이번에도 또 불평하러 갔어요
I was beaten by my father again
나는 또 아버지에게 구타당했다.
In our Yingzhou
우리 잉저우에서는
There is also a small hillside
작은 언덕도 있고
behind the woods
숲 뒤에
spring time
봄 시간
The hillside is full of wild flowers
산기슭에는 야생화가 가득하다
When I was little I used to lead horses
나는 어렸을 때 말을 몰고 다녔어요
lying on the hillside
언덕에 누워
looking at the clouds in the sky
하늘의 구름을 바라보며
drifting slowly
천천히 표류하다
If I were a child
내가 어린아이였다면
It would be nice to know you
당신을 알면 좋을 것 같아요
Not always
항상 그런 것은 아니다
Maybe when I was a kid
아마 내가 어렸을 때였을 거야
Do you still find me annoying?
아직도 내가 짜증나나요?
When you first met me
당신이 나를 처음 만났을 때
You still hate me
아직도 날 싫어하잖아
I hate it so much that my teeth itch
너무 싫어서 이가 가려워
How bad were you then?
그때 얼마나 나빴나요?
Kick me into the well
나를 우물에 차서 넣어라
It made me soak in cold water for a long time
찬물에 오래 담가두게 되더라구요
Then you still treat me
그럼 넌 아직도 날 대하는구나
Kicked into the river
강에 발을 찼다
Then do I want it now?
그럼 지금 내가 원하는 걸까?
I'll give you a couple of slaps to vent your anger.
분노를 풀기 위해 뺨을 몇 대 주겠습니다.
Bring your face closer
얼굴을 가까이 가져오세요
You said you can't play but can't play
너는 놀 수 없다고 말했지만 놀 수는 없다.
Why can I only shoot but not play?
왜 촬영만 할 수 있고 플레이는 할 수 없나요?
I do not care
난 상관 없어
you played me
당신은 나를 가지고 놀았어
I'm about to bounce back
나 다시 돌아오려고 해
look
바라보다
I let you play
놀게 놔뒀어
Miss
놓치다
Qiucui
치우추이
I finally saw you
드디어 당신을 봤어요
Why are you back?
왜 돌아왔나요?
I'm not asking you to stay in Aoguan
나는 당신에게 Aoguan에 머물라고 요청하지 않습니다
Are you taking care of His Highness Prince Liang?
양 왕자 전하를 돌보고 있습니까?
His Royal Highness the King of Liang
양왕 전하
Was taken to Luoyang
낙양으로 이송됨
What kind of king is Lin?
린은 어떤 왕인가?
He is the son of His Highness Prince Liang
그는 양 왕자 전하의 아들입니다.
He personally brought troops and horses
그는 직접 군대와 말을 데려왔다.
Picked up at Aoguan
아오관(Aoguan)에서 픽업함
King Lin Er
린 어 왕
Picked up His Royal Highness Prince Liang
양왕 전하를 모셔오다
It’s King Lin Er
그것은 Lin Er 왕입니다.
Just afraid
그냥 두려워
This storm is coming again
이번 폭풍 또 오고 있어
Why is he so troubled?
그는 왜 그렇게 괴로워합니까?
Miss, you have already gone home
아가씨, 이미 집에 가셨군요
This incense burner is so exquisite
이 향로가 너무 고급스러워요
That was sent by my father
그건 아버지가 보내주신 거야
master
주인
The master is so kind to the lady
주인님이 아주머니에게 너무 친절하시네요
Na Fuzhong
나 푸중
No one will dare to look down on the young lady anymore.
더 이상 누구도 감히 그 아가씨를 얕잡아 볼 수 없을 것입니다.
for father
아버지를 위해
a useful daughter
유용한 딸
She is a good daughter
그녀는 좋은 딸이다
We have discussed it with Mr. Gu
우리는 구 선생님과 그것에 대해 논의했습니다.
I'll ask Miss Gu tomorrow
내일 구씨한테 물어볼게
Accompany the Prime Minister out of the house
집 밖으로 총리를 동행
Let Mr. Gu just pretend to go to the silk shop
구 선생님이 실크 가게에 가는 척 하게 해주세요
tailor-made
맞춤형
Our store has various kinds of silk and satin
저희 가게에는 다양한 종류의 실크와 새틴이 있습니다
For your choice
당신의 선택을 위해
Please come inside
안으로 들어오세요
Pillar
기둥
Greeting guests
손님을 맞이하다
Let me help you measure the size
사이즈 측정 도와드릴게요
My father doesn’t like to be touched by outsiders.
우리 아버지는 외부인이 만지는 것을 좋아하지 않습니다.
It's better for me to measure my father's body.
아버지의 신체를 측정하는 것이 더 좋습니다.
good
좋은
two persons
두 사람
Please come here for measuring.
측정하러 오세요.
Mr. Gu entered the interior
구씨가 실내로 들어섰다
Behind the screen, blocking everyone’s view
화면 뒤에서 모두의 시야를 차단
Start measuring
측정 시작
My Cui Jiajun is in Beijing
나의 Cui Jiajun은 베이징에 있습니다
An old acquaintance, Koushiro
오랜 지인 코시로
Best at ventriloquism
복화술에 최고
Let him pretend to be Gu Xiang
Gu Xiang인 척 하게 해주세요
and Gu Waanniang’s voice
그리고 Gu Waanniang의 목소리
What's in this store?
이 가게에는 무엇이 있나요?
Sober and varied materials
차분하고 다양한 소재
Look
바라보다
Pick something up for your mother too
엄마한테도 뭐 좀 사오세요
Father
아버지
I think this is pretty good
내 생각엔 이게 꽤 좋은 것 같아
But this treasure pattern
그런데 이 보물무늬
Seems a bit too old-fashioned
좀 너무 낡은 것 같긴 한데
Father
아버지
Take a look at this
이것을보세요
This can be used as a robe
이건 가운으로 사용해도 돼요
very good very good
아주 좋아 아주 좋아
Then let’s choose this one.
그럼 이걸 선택하자.